[{"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a92", "question": "What was Clarence Rutherford\u2019s nickname on the TV show \"Leave it to Beaver\"?", "answer": "Lumpy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a731", "question": "Miami is the capital of which US state?", "answer": "None, Miami is not a capital city", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398b7", "question": "In which movie does Clint Eastwood utter the line 'Go ahead, make my day\"?", "answer": "Sudden Impact", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6a0f520565ad31a57c79e", "question": "Who was the first woman to appear on American currency?", "answer": "Pocahontas", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a384", "question": "What is the capital of Ontario?", "answer": "Toronto", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59637168967692ea851899ba", "question": "When Easter baskets were first introduced, they were made to look like a what?", "answer": "Bird\u2019s nest", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a15", "question": "What Tchaikovsky ballet includes \"Dance of the Sugar-Plum Fairy\" and \"Waltz of the Flowers\"?", "answer": "The Nutcracker", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a33e", "question": "What musical parodist sang the Halloween song \"Nature Trail to Hell\"?", "answer": "Weird Al Yankovic", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa3a", "question": "What is the capital of Barbados?", "answer": "Bridgetown", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339763", "question": "Although directed by Brian de Palma, which Hollywood director wrote Scarface?", "answer": "Oliver Stone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c602", "question": "The moons of Uranus are named after characters from the works of what writers?", "answer": "Shakespeare and Alexander Pope", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a162baaf01ec323f849172b", "question": "What type of creature is a Silverback?", "answer": "A gorilla", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ebd", "question": "John Carpenter's \"Assault on Precinct 13\" is an homage to what classic Howard Hawks western?", "answer": "Rio Bravo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a935", "question": "What is the only nation that shares a land border with Qatar?", "answer": "Saudi Arabia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58dba39f874c93a3298b213e", "question": "Who was nicknamed La Pucelle d'Orl\u00e9ans?", "answer": "Joan of Arc", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe000611cf6db9ac4808d10", "question": "When was Hong Kong transferred from Britain to China?", "answer": "1997", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff0b810e662d71a5365101c", "question": "Which political fiction novel won the 1947 Pulitzer prize?", "answer": "\"All the King's Men\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a896", "question": "What city is home to the Milad Tower?", "answer": "Tehran", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fdc11b0469bb8041d07a078", "question": "In Easter celebrations in Germany, what do children decorate trees with?", "answer": "Eggs", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e1a", "question": "The TV show \"Ugly Betty\" is based on what Venezuelan show?", "answer": "Yo soy Betty la fea", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecccdaec223966ae8f88a6", "question": "What country does \"The Hunger Games\" take place in?", "answer": "Panem", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecc095ec223966ae8f885c", "question": "What bedtime story does Gertie's mom read to her in \"E.T. the Extra-Terrestrial\"?", "answer": "\"Peter Pan\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6a65620565ad31a57c7d7", "question": "What was the name of the U.S ship on which the five Sullivan brothers died after it was torpedoed by the Japanese  during WWII?", "answer": "USS Juneau CL-52", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe699d920565ad31a57c74c", "question": "Who killed the Portuguese explorer Ferdinand Magellan in 1521?", "answer": "Lapu-Lapu", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339669", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", which breed of dog is Santa's Little Helper?", "answer": "Greyhound", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e9d", "question": "What movie did the villain Alonzo Harris appear in?", "answer": "Training Day", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea3d8fff048f679a45ab4f", "question": "Which insect is the closest relative to the grasshopper?", "answer": "Cockroach", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b990", "question": "Which NBA team plays its home games at the Barclays Centre?", "answer": "Brooklyn Nets", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7be71877e98cb97778960", "question": "What is the coldest sea on Earth?", "answer": "White Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8b32d01dd7bf43be5e7a9", "question": "What did Prince Harry use as his last name while serving in the military?", "answer": "Wales", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339223", "question": "What is the name of Futurama's first episode aired in 1999?", "answer": "Space Pilot 3000", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab2f", "question": "Which ocean is the region of Melanesia located in?", "answer": "Pacific", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b003", "question": "In 1810, New York overtook what city as America's most populated city?", "answer": "Philadelphia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9f4", "question": "What Mojave Desert city has a name meaning \"the meadows\" in Spanish?", "answer": "Las Vegas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3a9", "question": "What US city is nicknamed \"The Big Peach\"?", "answer": "Atlanta", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af60", "question": "On what day was Nelson Mandela released from prison?", "answer": "February 11, 1990", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fc2f025cee580c7f8fd1e4a", "question": "What famous general was nicknamed \"Old blood and guts\" by his men?", "answer": "General George S. Patton", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7ea", "question": "What are the two most common coffee bean types?", "answer": "Arabica and Robusta", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad51", "question": "What U.S. president signed the bill that began Medicaid benefits?", "answer": "Lyndon B. Johnson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390a6", "question": "Who wrote the opera \"Madama Butterfly\"?", "answer": "Giacomo Puccini", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b28b", "question": "What famous horse belonged to Caligula?", "answer": "Incitatus", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7c4", "question": "Who won a Nobel Prize for discovering Penicillin?", "answer": "Alexander Fleming", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe69b0620565ad31a57c75a", "question": "What was Germany's code name for its planned invasion of the the United Kingdom during World War II?", "answer": "Operation Sea Lion", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ab1", "question": "What type of family pet gets boiled in a pot of water in the movie \"Fatal Attraction\"?", "answer": "A rabbit", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdc10e0469bb8041d07a071", "question": "What is used to thicken gazpacho?", "answer": "Bread", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59f9b844364247bf200fb87e", "question": "What year did Valve release the Steam platform?", "answer": "2003", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca75", "question": "How many feet are there in a fathom?", "answer": "6", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e8", "question": "What does M.C. stand for in M.C. Escher's name?", "answer": "Maurits Cornelis", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8cb", "question": "In the world of sports, what does the abbreviation NCAA stand for?", "answer": "National Collegiate Athletic Association", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2cb", "question": "Who played the female lead in the 1947 film \"The Bishop's Wife\"?", "answer": "Loretta Young", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58b8d6aa2b42d4a3561a9f06", "question": "West Swan is a suburb in which Australian city?", "answer": "Perth", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59071d2c3745b36be73039d5", "question": "What Soviet operation forced over 2,000 scientists and engineers to relocate from East Germany to Russia to work on missile design and production?", "answer": "Operation Osoaviakhim", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bff8", "question": "Bibliophobia is a fear or hatred of what?", "answer": "Books", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339290", "question": "On the TV show \"Lost\", what group conducts scientific experiments on the island?", "answer": "Dharma Initiative", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58c89d11011619dd6d415482", "question": "While pretending to be an inner city calculus teacher, what was Eric Cartman\u2019s catch phrase in South Park?", "answer": "How do I reach these keeeds?", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6aa0220565ad31a57c80e", "question": "The United Nations replaced what organization?", "answer": "The League of Nations", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b29c", "question": "What position was only ever held by Louisiana-born Varina Howell?", "answer": "The First Lady of the Confederacy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b5e", "question": "How many lines are in a limerick?", "answer": "5", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396f3", "question": "What was John Wayne\u2019s nickname?", "answer": "The Duke", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7cd4c877e98cb97778a34", "question": "What was the first country to declare internet a legal right?", "answer": "Finland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395f3", "question": "In The Simpsons, who do Jumbo and Kearney usually hang around with?", "answer": "Dolph", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c4c6877e98cb977789a6", "question": "Which city has a building nicknamed \"the Walkie-Talkie building\"?", "answer": "London", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be3a", "question": "How many players are there in a standard ultimate frisbee team?", "answer": "Seven", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b15", "question": "In which decade did the \"Peanuts\" comic strip debut?", "answer": "1950s", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394c1", "question": "Who was Spenser's sidekick in the TV show \"Spenser: For Hire\"?", "answer": "Hawk", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fdf", "question": "What instrument did Lionel Hampton introduce to jazz in 1930?", "answer": "The vibraphone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3d1", "question": "Which is the only independent state smaller than Monaco?", "answer": "The Vatican", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5c77ceaf24f0f7a362efd548", "question": "The CN Tower is in which Canadian city?", "answer": "Toronto", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7c98f877e98cb977789f6", "question": "In which city was the oldest university in Scandinavia founded in 1477?", "answer": "Uppsala", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e37", "question": "Who plays drums on the Beatles track \"Back in the U.S.S.R.\"?", "answer": "Paul McCartney", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b545", "question": "What does Canada mean in Iroquoian?", "answer": "Village", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a57d", "question": "Kodiak Island is the largest island in which US state?", "answer": "Alaska", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1cb", "question": "Oslo's Holocaust research center is the former home of what firing squad victim?", "answer": "Vidkun Quisling", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe4dd4106d333868d34d6ff", "question": "In which country did Buddhism originate?", "answer": "Nepal", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a31b", "question": "Who played the role of Jack Tripper on the TV show \"Three's Company\"?", "answer": "John Ritter", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb8a", "question": "What type of stuffed animal does an arctophile collect?", "answer": "Teddy bears", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6db", "question": "What Ivy League school is located in Hanover, New Hampshire?", "answer": "Darthmouth College", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe4e0e006d333868d34d722", "question": "\"An eye for an eye and a tooth for a tooth\" is a well-known phrase from what collection of 282 laws?", "answer": "The Code of Hammurabi", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b557", "question": "What flavoured jellybeans were created for United States' President Ronald Reagan's inauguration?", "answer": "Blueberry", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339370", "question": "What movie won the Oscar for Best Visual Effects in 1978?", "answer": "Superman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ae9299574a5ce6b56b822f", "question": "Who wrote \"The Rose Tattoo\"?", "answer": "Tennessee Williams", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff51a8aff04d658268c9306", "question": "Odysseus left home to fight in what war?", "answer": "Trojan War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e5a", "question": "What literary work inspired Franz Ferdinand's \"Love and Destroy\" song?", "answer": "The Master and Margarita", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59009009cf842fa4c4ba96c3", "question": "Who wrote the humorous novel \"The Life and Opinions of Tristram Shandy, Gentleman\"?", "answer": "Laurence Sterne", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339683", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is the name of Homer's snow-plowing service?", "answer": "Mr. Plow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c0c1877e98cb9777896e", "question": "What is the least populated continguous U.S. state?", "answer": "Wyoming", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5feddbbe6ce05a3942286d93", "question": "According to the Jim Croce song, what is Leroy Brown meaner than?", "answer": "Junk yard dog", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dd2", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"honcho\"?", "answer": "Japanese", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe6aa8820565ad31a57c81a", "question": "In which German city did Joseph Stalin, Winston Churchill and President Franklin D Roosevelt meet in 1945?", "answer": "Potsdam", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fdfba17003d27d341092bc3", "question": "What three countries border Luxembourg?", "answer": "France, Germany, and Belgium", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea79e5ff048f679a45abe4", "question": "As what type of beans are chickpeas also known as?", "answer": "Garbanzo", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a9e96237ccba3ffe45786e9", "question": "In Greek mythology, who did Athena turn into a spider?", "answer": "Arachne", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a97d", "question": "What nation's legislative body is named The Jatiyo Sangshad?", "answer": "Bangladesh", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338daa", "question": "What object did photographer Andres Serrano place in a glass of his own urine in 1989?", "answer": "A crucifix", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fede1eb6ce05a3942286dc8", "question": "In \"Frosty the Snowman\", what are Frosty's eyes made of?", "answer": "Coal", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5bfdffddb668d7dfe168b5bc", "question": "Chablis wine comes from which French wine region?", "answer": "Burgundy", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae89", "question": "What military alliance did the US join in 1949?", "answer": "NATO", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58f5662b33a95c66dc4fe760", "question": "Mentu is the Egyptian god of what?", "answer": "War", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acf0", "question": "Which president signed the legislation to create the Secret Service?", "answer": "Abraham Lincoln", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7cc", "question": "What is a traditional karate uniform called?", "answer": "Gi", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c170", "question": "Karakul and Dorset are types of what?", "answer": "Sheep", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe9f3f5ff048f679a45aac5", "question": "What year was the fire extinguisher invented?", "answer": "1723", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0ee", "question": "Leukophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "The color white", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5937eacc08d98002fdd633a8", "question": "What were the nicknames of the Dean brothers who pitched for the St. Louis Cardinals?", "answer": "Daffy and Dizzy", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe905ba01dd7bf43be5e880", "question": "What does FLOTUS stand for?", "answer": "First Lady Of The United States", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fbe", "question": "What instrument did bandleader Glenn Miller play?", "answer": "Trombone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefc4176ce05a3942286f2c", "question": "Who recorded the song \"Ain't That A Kick In The Head\"?", "answer": "Dean Martin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395c0", "question": "In The Simpsons, who is Cletus, the slack-jawed yokel married to?", "answer": "Brandine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5906830bff9c0647b50a80a3", "question": "Which actress, portraying an Alderaan princess, passed away in December, 2016?", "answer": "Carrie Fisher", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad9dda8e748bb36357acde2", "question": "What subatomic particle determines isotope?", "answer": "Neutron", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1a0", "question": "Who Wrote Aretha Franklins \"Respect\"?", "answer": "Otis Redding", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff66ae952a821ff76ae8b0b", "question": "Confucianism effectively became the common philosophy of the Chinese empire during which dynasty?", "answer": "Han Dynasty", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b571b3b67df192a942e3366", "question": "What is the name of the boy appearing on the Cracker Jack box?", "answer": "Sailor Jack", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133956d", "question": "Which cowboy musical artist first recorded the song, Here Comes Santa Claus?", "answer": "Gene Autry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe698b420565ad31a57c737", "question": "Which goddess helped guide Odysseus back home?", "answer": "Athena", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e1d", "question": "What Grimm's fairy-tale character is named for a vegetable craved by her pregnant mother?", "answer": "Rapunzel", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b85", "question": "What is the name of the rabbit in the movie \"Bambi\"?", "answer": "Thumper", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015e63afe83fe1f2a824bc9", "question": "Who ultimately succeeded King Alfred the Great as \"King of the Anglo-Saxons\"?", "answer": "Edward the Elder", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e9", "question": "What was writer and war hero T.E. Lawrence popularly known as?", "answer": "Lawrence of Arabia", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fed2bd0ec223966ae8f8913", "question": "In the film \"Dances with Wolves,\" what happens to Dunbar's diary?", "answer": "It's used as toilet paper.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6003984d57a0e35c43f8389b", "question": "What is the term for an artistic process that involves shooting ink at a blank piece of paper?", "answer": "Bulletism\u00a0-- The result is a type of ink blot. The artist can then develop images based on what is seen.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acea", "question": "Which president's wife helped fund the war effort by auctioning wool from sheep grazing on the White House lawn?", "answer": "Woodrow Wilson's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab63", "question": "In what city would you find the infamous Alcatraz?", "answer": "San Francisco", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b152", "question": "In what year did Atlanta become the fifth capital of Georgia?", "answer": "1868", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a288", "question": "\"Next\" and \"Paycheck\" are films based on stories by which science-fiction author?", "answer": "Philip K. Dick", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339388", "question": "What is the Voight-Kampff machine in the movie \"Blade Runner\"?", "answer": "A lie detector", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a1e1d9cb5a031299b74573c", "question": "What century did the Europeans dicover the Okapi?", "answer": "20th Century", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fecd41bec223966ae8f88ca", "question": "Some of the musical compositions for \"The Hateful Eight\" are unused scores from what movie?", "answer": "\"The Thing\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c872", "question": "What piece of technology did IBM develop in 1973 that they nicknamed Winchester?", "answer": "A disk drive", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b715", "question": "The album, Sacred Arias was released by what blind Italian tenor?", "answer": "Andrea Bocelli", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aeeb", "question": "Which U.S. President ended his country's participation in the Vietnam War?", "answer": "Richard Nixon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3e3", "question": "At what age did Buffalo Bill become a rider for the Pony Express?", "answer": "14", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133959e", "question": "Who appears alongside Jim Carrey in the 1994 movie \"Dumb and Dumber\"?", "answer": "Jeff Daniels", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff14708b0ee8c595b6d39c2", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Les Mis\u00e9rables\"?", "answer": "Victor Hugo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a834", "question": "Which two countries does The Netherlands border?", "answer": "Belgium and Germany", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339767", "question": "In Old School, what actor is caught streaking and says, \"Come on snoop, snoopaloop, bring your green hat\"?", "answer": "Will Ferrell", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8d9", "question": "On a standard Monopoly board, what are the two least expensive properties?", "answer": "Mediterranean and Baltic", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b353", "question": "Who assassinated John Lennon?", "answer": "Mark David Chapman", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aba4", "question": "What country is located immediately north of Sudan?", "answer": "Egypt", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b323315bf195a31e15d7397", "question": "Blitz, Boondock, Bristol, Scrunge and Squop are terms used in what game?", "answer": "Tiddlywinks", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a11", "question": "What crashes from the ceiling to provide one of the highlights of Lloyd Weber's \"The Phantom of the Opera\"?", "answer": "Chandelier", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ec", "question": "What is the technical name of the pound sign?", "answer": "Octothorpe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a47a", "question": "In which country is the Simpson Desert located?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adba", "question": "What was the first US city to have a subway system?", "answer": "Boston", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c991", "question": "What is the young of a pigeon called?", "answer": "Squab", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5937eea308d98002fdd633d6", "question": "\"Confide in Me\" was a hit in 1994 for which singer?", "answer": "Kylie Minogue", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc3d", "question": "Professional tennis player, Rafael Nadal, is of what nationality?", "answer": "Spanish", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b8d", "question": "What love\u00adstruck Warner Brothers cartoon character often chased a black cat named Penelope?", "answer": "Pepe Le Pew", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396fb", "question": "After his stint as Robin, what persona new did Dick Grayson adopt?", "answer": "Nightwing", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600f7493a9e54d890926f6fa", "question": "In Texas, it\u2019s illegal to swear in front of what?", "answer": "A corpse", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0d7", "question": "What fruit is \"Citrus grandis\"?", "answer": "Pomelo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a390", "question": "Where in London are the Crown Jewels kept?", "answer": "The Tower of London", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be44", "question": "What is the only fruit to be ever banned from airplanes?", "answer": "Durian", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fedd8656ce05a3942286d6e", "question": "Which player was selected first in the 1983 NBA Draft?", "answer": "Ralph Sampson", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffcfe639dc5ec6cd98a832a", "question": "Which character is pregnant at the beginning of The Grapes of Wrath?", "answer": "Rose of Sharon", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c738", "question": "Dry Ice is the solid form of what chemical compound?", "answer": "Carbon dioxide", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7ce56877e98cb97778a40", "question": "Which is the longest river in the Philippines?", "answer": "Cagayan River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a171", "question": "What is the name of Marty's band in the film \"Back To The Future\"?", "answer": "The Pinheads", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ffc", "question": "Excluding Rudolph, how many reindeer pull Santa's sleigh?", "answer": "Eight", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac08", "question": "What ocean does the Congo River flow into?", "answer": "Atlantic Ocean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b94a", "question": "Who was the jeweller to the Russian Court famous Easter eggs?", "answer": "Peter Carl Faberge", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9f5", "question": "In what U.S. City was the Rag\u00fa brand of Italian-style sauces first produced?", "answer": "Rochester, New York", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0f5", "question": "In 1976-1977 season in 80 games, the Montreal Canadiens set the NHL record for how many points in a season?", "answer": "132", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60173e6544491cbd7c5a17b0", "question": "The Wright brothers originally ran what kind of business?", "answer": "Bicycle repair and design -- The name of their business was Wright Cycle Company.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3d5", "question": "Who was British Prime Minister at the outbreak of WWI?", "answer": "Herbert Henry Asquith", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac70", "question": "When were scissors first invented?", "answer": "Around 1500 BC", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fc2f4a5cee580c7f8fd1e59", "question": "What was the name of the commission that investigated the assassination of John F. Kennedy?", "answer": "Warren Commission", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b459", "question": "Herodotus is commonly referred to as what?", "answer": "The Father of History", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339225", "question": "Who plays the role of Craig the puppeteer's wife in \"Being John Malkovich\"?", "answer": "Cameron Diaz", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339476", "question": "What is the name of the character Samuel L. Jackson play in the movie \"Unbreakable\"?", "answer": "Elijah", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b32344dbf195a31e15d73a4", "question": "What band's songs include \"Get Down and Get With It\" and \"Mama Weer All Crazee Now\"?", "answer": "Slade", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395b5", "question": "In The Simpsons, what is the three-eyed fish named?", "answer": "Blinky", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "597cd690e347d002c297e4bb", "question": "Collectively, what name is given to the first ten of the amendments to the United States Constitution?", "answer": "The Bill of Rights", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bba9", "question": "What country produced Saab automobiles?", "answer": "Sweden", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d35", "question": "Who's responsible for performing \"The Ballad of The Green Berets\"?", "answer": "Barry Sadler", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca42", "question": "Which vital organ does the adjective renal refer to?\u00a0", "answer": "Kidney\u00a0", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133baf4", "question": "What cartoon character is used by Owens-Corning in ads for its insulation products?", "answer": "Pink Panther", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339275", "question": "On the TV show \"Next Iron Chef\", Celine Tio was eliminated how many episodes before the finale?", "answer": "One", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe65689ae7e414034b5aecb", "question": "What year did the Battle of Agincourt take place?", "answer": "1415", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339719", "question": "At what age did Ray Charles become totally blind?", "answer": "7", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ec1", "question": "What is the stage name of rapper Jayceon Taylor?", "answer": "The Game", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339042", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"The Naked and the Dead\"?", "answer": "Norman Mailer", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c965", "question": "Aviatophobia is a fear of what?", "answer": "Flying", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0bf", "question": "What famous chemist died in 1934 from a blood disease contracted by the effects of radiation exposure?", "answer": "Marie Curie", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea7eb9ff048f679a45ac12", "question": "What color is Absinthe?", "answer": "Green", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5af98549aeb0982ee455954d", "question": "Which video game released in 2017 has an animation style similar to the 1930\u2019s?", "answer": "Cuphead", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef937a6ce05a3942286e8f", "question": "What is the name of the giant mammoth-like creatures used as war animals in \"Lord of the Rings: The Return of the King\"?", "answer": "Oliphaunts", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e4b", "question": "What athlete had a part in the movie \"Lock, Stock, and Two Smoking Barrels\"?", "answer": "Vinnie Jones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a071", "question": "Who filled in for Ringo Starr on the Beatles' 1964 world tour?", "answer": "Jimmie Nicol", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe738e8eec85e375820b26a", "question": "Where is the USA's first ski town located?", "answer": "Woodstock, Vermont", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5b8", "question": "Zion National Park is located in which US state?", "answer": "Utah", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a087", "question": "Where are Rocket J. Squirrel and Bullwinkle Moose from?", "answer": "Frostbite Falls", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a9f", "question": "John Reed's book \"Ten Days That Shook the World\" was an eyewitness account of which event?", "answer": "The Russian Revolution", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339895", "question": "The line \"Greed, for a lack of better word, is good!\" can be heard in what movie?", "answer": "Wall Street", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1d9", "question": "What is Merlin's owl name in Disney's film \"The Sword in the Stone\"?", "answer": "Archimedes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4d1", "question": "Angel Falls, the highest waterfall in the world, is located in what country?", "answer": "Venezuela", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "592204f8a4edfd43a087ade7", "question": "Who was the top scorer at the 2014 FIFA World Cup?", "answer": "James Rodriguez", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be9c", "question": "Who washes his hands in Matthew 27:24?", "answer": "Pontius Pilate", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0b6", "question": "What is the name of the artist Prince's recording studio?", "answer": "Paisley Park", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a9e942c7ccba3ffe45786cf", "question": "What is the chemical symbol for Californium?", "answer": "Cf", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338acd", "question": "Author Rudyard Kipling was born in what country?", "answer": "India", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea3f6fff048f679a45ab5e", "question": "Who was the Clark University physicist responsible for \"A Method of Reaching Extreme Altitudes\"?", "answer": "Robert Goddard", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad58", "question": "Frank Wathernam was the last inmate to leave what infamous prison?", "answer": "Alcatraz", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5e7", "question": "Bill Cosby is a famous alumnus of what Philadelphia university?", "answer": "Temple University", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b38", "question": "What Blue Collar Comedy Tour comedian is known for his routine concerning \"Tater Salad\"?", "answer": "Ron White", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59f9bbce364247bf200fb8a8", "question": "Lusaka is the capital of which African country?", "answer": "Zambia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59a5529e3e1c6f9840ba3198", "question": "What is South Korea's telephone calling code?", "answer": "82", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dda", "question": "What army is invading Pepperland in the Beatles film \"Yellow Submarine\"?", "answer": "The Blue Meanies", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9e0", "question": "What term is given to the scientific study of all aspects of the life of fungi?", "answer": "Mycology", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394bc", "question": "What is the name of Jack's pet parrot on the TV show \"Will & Grace\"?", "answer": "Guspo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339455", "question": "What musical starred Vanessa Redgrave as Guinevere?", "answer": "Camelot", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdc7", "question": "What is the primary ingredient in the silvery amalgam used in dental restoration?", "answer": "Mercury", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dc5", "question": "What double-word song title was a hit single by Santana?", "answer": "Maria Maria", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f8f", "question": "Who composed the opera \"A Village Romeo and Juliet\"?", "answer": "Frederick Delius", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8afb901dd7bf43be5e78a", "question": "What is the term for a word that is spelled the same forwards and backwards?", "answer": "Palindrome", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59decf99ea2747c8aff16d20", "question": "Myomancy is the practice of what?", "answer": "Reading omens from the behavior of rats or mice", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb99", "question": "A.J. Foyt was the first person to win what annual competition four times?", "answer": "Indianapolis 500", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391d8", "question": "Which year was the first Indiana Jones movie released?", "answer": "1981", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea3a63ff048f679a45ab2b", "question": "What does the human lacrimal gland produce?", "answer": "Tears", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5c90d62c52800b05cac20f1f", "question": "What two planets in our Solar System possess no moons?", "answer": "Mercury and Venus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd50", "question": "The Fields Medal is an award given in what field?", "answer": "Mathematics", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe25717658e585fda9cfa3a", "question": "What destructive party item was banned in Hollywood on Halloween starting in 2004?", "answer": "Silly String", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba4e", "question": "What hall-of-fame quarterback joined the Denver Broncos in 1983?", "answer": "John Elway", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba52", "question": "What black and white bird is the official state bird of Minnesota?", "answer": "Common Loon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58b371951c3f17ccc40c8e1f", "question": "Which Irish poet said \"There are no strangers here; Only friends you have not yet met.\"?", "answer": "William Butler Yeats", "category": "art"}, {"id": "590681e5ff9c0647b50a8098", "question": "What fictional town is the Netflix series \"Stranger Things\" based in?", "answer": "Hawkins, Indiana", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1ce", "question": "Creme de Cacao, fresh cream and what other ingredient are combined to make a Grasshopper cocktail?", "answer": "Creme de Menthe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7c4dc877e98cb977789a8", "question": "Which US state's motto is \"Live free or die\"?", "answer": "New Hampshire", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c552", "question": "To be classified as perennial, a plant must have a life cycle of more than how many years?", "answer": "Two", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7c6e0877e98cb977789c3", "question": "In which English town can you attend the annual Jane Austen Festival?", "answer": "Bath", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea4297ff048f679a45ab7a", "question": "Which age is known as the \"Age of Fish\"?", "answer": "Paleozoic Era", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6e0", "question": "What decade witnessed the invention of the automatic bowling pinsetter?", "answer": "1930s", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe6a58c20565ad31a57c7ce", "question": "What dessert did Margaret Thatcher help develop?", "answer": "Soft-serve ice cream", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8a9f601dd7bf43be5e754", "question": "If there are six apples, and you take away four, how many apples do you have?", "answer": "Four", "category": "general"}, {"id": "597cde15e347d002c297e4f8", "question": "Who wrote the classic science fiction novel \"Helliconia Winter\"?", "answer": "Brian W. Aldiss", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c779", "question": "What aquatic reptile can hold its breath under water for up to 15 minutes?", "answer": "The crocodile", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a4a999b61d1b4d384d5d69d", "question": "Who portrayed Marshal Matt Dillon in the TV show \"Gunsmoke\"?", "answer": "James Arness", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "597ddccb77980686f722d17a", "question": "What war saw the use of tanks in battle for first time?", "answer": "World War I", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff3c2c54f032c0db195b485", "question": "In 1912, what did a Paris orphanage give away as prizes when it held a raffle to raise money?", "answer": "Live babies", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339878", "question": "In Star Trek, what planet is Spock from?", "answer": "Vulcan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7ca88877e98cb97778a06", "question": "What country is made up of 3,000 islands, the largest being Honshu, Hokkaido, Kyushu and Shikoku?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396af", "question": "What actor founded the Purple Rose Theater Company in Michigan?", "answer": "Jeff Daniels", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdd6", "question": "Why were the earliest English umbrellas nicknamed \"Robinsons\"?", "answer": "For Robinson Crusoe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59524316736d4be723796b66", "question": "Which \"Doctor Who\" actor was the voice of \"Spotty\" from the Welsh cartoon \"SuperTed\"?", "answer": "Jon Pertwee", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c42d", "question": "How many calves does the average giraffe mother give birth to each time?", "answer": "One", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59a7f64f6f5f79087132fb43", "question": "Which actress who played Alia Atreides in 1984's \"Dune\" and went on to star in 1998's \"Urban Legend\"?", "answer": "Alicia Witt", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e0a", "question": "What 1984 hit repeats the phrase \"Come on, shine your heavenly body tonight\"?", "answer": "Lucky Star", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c877", "question": "What disease does the \"tine test\" detect?", "answer": "Tuberculosis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338909", "question": "Who wrote \"The Hunchback of Notre Dame\"?", "answer": "Victor Hugo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0de", "question": "Where exactly were the \"Bee Gees\" band members actually born?", "answer": "The Isle Of Man", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ae94aa574a5ce6b56b824a", "question": "What was the full name of Dr. Henry Jekyll's alter ego?", "answer": "Edward Hyde", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6e7", "question": "What is a spinnaker on a boat?", "answer": "Type of sail", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c529", "question": "How many times does the average heart beat each day?", "answer": "100,000", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fef96566ce05a3942286e9c", "question": "The novel \"Flowers for Algernon\" became which major motion picture?", "answer": "\"Charly\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5da855dd1aec824685d88d03", "question": "What is the most common street name in the United States?", "answer": "Park, according to a Washington Post study", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c477", "question": "What is cryogenics the study of?", "answer": "Production of low temperatures", "category": "science"}]